# Juan Martín Guillén

## Software Solutions Manager

<u>juanmartinguillen@yahoo.com.ar</u> - +54 9 11 6867 6483 - Gascón 514, CABA Argentinian, married and father of one son. Born on September 9th 1976.

Abstract: 25+ years experienced in the IT field with breadth of experience across different Software disciplines within the Health, Retail, Distribution and Fintech domains. Multi cultural and multi disciplinary work experience. Demonstrated excellence in research and development, technical leadership, superior customer satisfaction and providing novel solutions to complex issues. Areas of interest include, researching new technologies, customer relationship management, training, mentoring and people development.

### Education:

- E.N.E.T. №1, San Isidro (1995): Electronic Technician (Data Communications)
- · University of Morón (2008): Commercial Real Estate Agent.
- English: Fluent speaking/reading/writing
- · Portuguese: Intermediate speaking/reading/writing.

Specialties: Systems Engineering, Technical & People Leadership, Training, Customer Relationship Management.

#### Skills:

Skills:

• Systems Architecture

• Software Development

• Critical Thinking

• Active Listening Machine LearningDatabasesNetworking Technical Leadership Data Engineering Judgment and Decision Making
 Hiring

Technologies: Rust, JavaScript, Shell Scripting, PL/SQL, C, Python, Erlang/Elixir, PHP, MySQL/Maria, PostgreSQL, Oracle, MongoDB, Redis, Solaris, Linux, AIX, Windows, EMR, EC2, Lambda, S3, Redshift, RDS, Kinesis, Cloudformation, Route 53, Routing, Switching, SAN, NAS, Cisco CCNA, HA Proxy, Nginx, Git, Docker, Hadoop, Hive, Spark, Kafka, Airflow.

#### Experience:

Yabble - Marketing Services Company. 1/2020 - Today. Engineering Manager: Creating AI-powered Systems for customers. <u>Reference</u>: Diego Levin - CTO. - +64 21 205 9909 diego@yabblezone.net

Development Manager: Creating software solutions for big retail customers.

Reference: Osvaldo Ivani - Operations Manager. - +54 9 11 3175 4171

oivani@xncompany.com

XN Argentina S.A. - Technology Integrator.

AJC International, Inc. - Food & Logistics Company. 2007 - 2014.

Technical Lead: Building trading software and ERP solutions.

Reference: Pablo Mazzeo - Global Development Manager. - +54 9 11 6536 3931

pmazzeo@aicfood.com

Verizon Business. - Communications Company.

Oracle DBA Technical Lead: Managing hundreds of databases.

Reference: Murry Hall -Senior Manager. - +1-678-259-5436 (USA)

murry.hall@verizonbusiness.com

IT Training Center S.R.L. - IT Training Institute.

2004 - 2006.

2006 - 2007.

11/2014 - 12/2019.

Oracle, Linux & UNIX Trainer: Training technical teams. Reference: Ricardo Argüello - Training Manager. - 5218-6611

Red Link S.A. - ATM Network.

rarguello@ittc.com.ar

2002 - 2004.

Oracle and SQL Server DBA: Database administration for Financial apps.

Reference: Claudio Fernández - IT Services Manager. - 4317-1400

fernandez.claudio@redlink.com.ar